（アリババ）目が覚めて→
When I regained consciousness,
I learned that the king had passed away,
王が亡くなったっていう
知らせを聞いて→
and I ran from Balbadd.
その日のうちに
バルバッドを逃げ出したよ。
それから　オアシス都市群で→
I was hired by the Oasis City military,
lived with them, and started to save money.
日銭を稼いで暮らして。
I had always been fascinated by the dungeons,
昔からの憧れだったし
迷宮に入って→
and it was around this time that I
started to dream about finding one,
お宝を手に入れたら
償えるかも…→
and getting rich off the treasures inside.
なんて　思いはじめてさ。
But all I did was dream.
でも　やっぱ　口先ばっかで→
I lived day to day, just barely getting by.
ただ　毎日を
なんとなく　やり過ごしてたんだ→
Until I met you, Aladdin.
アラジン　お前に出会うまで。
I see...
（シンドバッド）なるほどねぇ→
He's an illegitimate child of the late king.
先王の隠し子だったか。
（ジャーファル）ちょっと　シン→
Sin, eavesdropping is not a habit one should nurture.
盗み聞きなんて　悪趣味ですよ。
Shh!
しっ！
But there is still something I don't understand.
≪（モルジアナ）でも　やはり
分からないことがあります。
If it is as you've said, Kassim betrayed you.
今の話のとおりなら→
カシムは
あなたを裏切った人です。
Why would you be a part of his Fog Troupe?
なのに　なぜ
あなたは　霧の団にいるのですか？
迷宮を攻略したあと
新しい一歩を踏み出す前に→
After we captured Amon's dungeon, I
wanted to set off on a new path, a right path.
But I wanted to take responsibility for my
previous mistakes first, so I returned to Balbadd.
けじめをつけようと思って
バルバッドに帰ったんだ。
What I found there was...
でも　そこで見たのは…。
♪♪～
akogare wo ima tsukanda
My desires are within reach.
♪♪～
daikansei no namari ni
If the loud, welcoming cheers
kokochiyoku utaretanara
shoot home straight into your heart,
saa tobikomou
then come and jump in!
ashita kara umare kawaru toka
People say they'll change the next day.
♪♪～
dareka ga mikiri tsuketa toka
But they give up so easily.
kono machi no style toka
That's just how it is here.
sonna mono ni nagasare tsuzukete
They get swept away by those excuses day by day.
kado no toreta genseki ni ha
They're nothing more than a chip, swept off the edge
kitto daremo you ha nai
and no longer needed by anyone.
♪♪～
fushigi to tobira no mukou ni ha
Guess what? Out there,
v.i.p nanoru yatsu ha naku
no one's swaggering around like a VIP.
daremo ga kunou no hate sa ore mo
Everyone suffers their own heartaches, myself included.
akogare wo ima tsukanda
But my desires are within reach.
♪♪～
mi wo yudanereba ii  kaji ha kono te ni
Throw yourself in with abandon. I've got the wheel.
mitsu kazoete the show time
On the count of three, it's show time!
daikansei no namari ni
If the loud, welcoming cheers
kokochiyoku utaretanara
shoot home straight into your heart,
saa tobikomou
then come and jump in!
♪♪～
9th Night
A Prince's Duty
Hey, what happened to Balbadd?
（回想）
((なあ　じいさん　バルバッドは→
どうして
こんなに　なっちまったんだ？))
Nothing in particular... After the former
king died, things just got worse and worse.
((どうしたもこうしたもねぇ。
先王が死んでからは→
めちゃくちゃになる一方さ))
（じいさん）((最近は
国を荒らし回る　賊も出るしな))
Lately, a group of thieves has surfaced, running a ruckus all over this country.
((賊？))
（じいさん）((ああ。→
Thieves?
こんな霧の夜には…))
On foggy nights like this one...
((うわ～！))
((霧の団だ！　霧の団が出たぞ！))
It's the Fog Troupe! The Fog Troupe's here!
((わあ～！))
((ひぃ～！))
((うっ…　うわっ！))
((くっ！))
♪♪～
((あっ…　カシム))
K-Kassim!
（カシム）((あっ　お前　アリババか？))
Is that... you, Alibaba?
Kassim!
カシム…。
ふっ。
Yeah.
At first, I thought he was the guy
throwing this country into chaos too.
俺も　最初は　国を荒らしてる
張本人だと思ってたさ。
But after talking to him, I realized how wrong I was.
でも　話を聞いたら
全然　違ってたんだ。
The one really at fault here is the government.
本当に悪いのは国の方だったんだ。
Whose...?
((これは？))
Mariam's.
（カシム）((マリアムだ))
((はっ))
（カシム）
((お前が王宮に行った次の年→
The year after you left for the palace,
スラムで　疫病がはやってよ。→
an epidemic swept through the slums.
なのに
国は　知らんぷりどころか→
Rather than just pretend they didn't know about it,
俺たちを隔離して
スラムに閉じ込めやがったんだ。→
the government tried to hide it, hide us, and completely closed off the slums.
We had no doctors, no medicine...
医者もいねぇ　薬もねぇ→
We didn't even have any food!
食い物だって…。→
そんななかで　どいつもこいつも
バタバタ死んでったよ。→
People died left and right.
Mariam started to throw up blood.
マリアムも　血ぃ吐いて→
She heaved, coughed, and was in so much pain...
苦しんで…　苦しんで　苦しんで))
((でも　俺は何も…→
But I couldn't...
何一つ　できなかったんだ…))
I couldn't do anything!
♪♪～
((マリアム…))
Mariam...
((お前　言ってたじゃねぇか
みんな　無事だって!!))
You said everyone was fine!!
What else could I have said?
((ほかに　何が言えた!?
みんな　死んじまったって…→
Did you want me to say they all died? That the country killed them all? Huh, Your Highness?!
国に殺されたって
言えばよかったのか!?→
王子様よぉ!!))
((うっ…))
((はぁ…))
((んん…))
After the epidemic died down, they cleaned the slums by burning everything to ashes.
（カシム）((疫病が落ち着いたあと
スラムは　焼き払われて→
Watching that, I realized something.
それを見て思ったよ
国は　俺たちのことなんか→
This country thinks of us as nothing more than trash.
ゴミ程度にしか
思ってないんだって。→
That's why I created the Fog Troupe.
だから
俺は　霧の団を組織したんだ。→
国に殺されちまう前に…→
To fight back.
To fight for our lives before the county cuts us down!
自分たちの力で
戦って生き延びるために))
Do you really think anything can be resolved like this?
((でも　こんなやり方で
なんとかできると思ってるのか？))
In the end, thieves are still thieves.
((盗賊は　所詮　盗賊だ。
いつか　狩られちまうぞ))
One day, you'll get caught.
（カシム）
((んなこたぁ　分かってるよ！→
Do you think I don't know that?
I don't need to hear it from you.
お前に言われるまでもねぇ。→
But I don't know what else to do!
でも　ほかに
やり方が分かんねぇんだよ))
((カシム…))
Kassim...
((あっ…　ははっ　そうだ→
Wait, that's it.
That's it!
そうだよな))
((あっ))
Alibaba, join the Fog Troupe!
((アリババ　霧の団に入って…→
いや　リーダーになってくれよ))
No, not even! Become our leader!
((王子のお前がいれば　霧の団は→
With a prince as our leader, we'd no longer be outlaws!
賊軍じゃなくなる))
((あっ))
俺を　裏切ったこともあった。
I know he betrayed me.
でも
話してて　やっぱり思ったんだ→
But after talking to him,
I realized that he's still my friend, and my family.
カシムは
俺の家族で　友達なんだって。
That's why I joined the Fog Troupe!
だから　霧の団に入ったんだ。
（アラジン・心の声）
≪なんだろう？　この感じ≫
What's this strange feeling...
I quickly took action.
俺は　すぐに行動を起こした。
In order to gain the support of the
people, we shared our spoils with them.
民衆の支持を得るために
盗んだ物資を…。
I feel like I've seen this before...
≪僕は　前にも　こんな場面を
見たことがある気がする≫
When the time is right, I will reveal my identity and go talk with Ahbmad.
機が熟したら
俺は　身分を明かして→
アブマドと　話をつけに行く。
I'm going to fix this, Aladdin!
俺はやるぜ　アラジン！
そっか…。
I see...
If your idea doesn't go according to plan, what will you do?
ねえ　もし
それでも　うまくいかなかったら→
どうするんだい？
それは…。
I'll...
Wanna start a war?
（カシム）((ひとつ
戦争でも　おっぱじめるか))
If you become controlled by your
anger and start a fight in your rage,
怒りに任せて　戦ってしまうと→
I have a feeling the result will be very sad.
とても悲しいことが
起こる気がするんだ。
But there's nothing I can do about that!
でも…
そんなの　しょうがねぇだろ。
This country's so messed up right now!
この国は　今　ひでぇんだよ！
Someone's gotta do something!
誰かが　やんなきゃダメなんだ！
もちろん→
I know this isn't the right way to do things,
正しいやり方じゃないのは
分かってるけど→
but I... I...
でも…　でも　俺は…。
I don't know what to do anymore!
もう　訳分かんねぇよ！
こんな情けねぇ俺が…。
I'm such a mess right now.
だから　今　お前たちには
会いたくなかったのに…。
That's why I didn't want to meet you guys yet!
頼むよ…　もう出てってくれよ！
Please... just get out of here!
この国から出てってくれ!!
Get out of Balbadd!
ゴン！
うっ！
Ow!
いってぇ！
落ち着いておくれよ
アリババくん。
Calm down, Alibaba.
確かに　この国の問題は
僕らには　とても難しい。
The problems this country is facing are very difficult.
でも　大丈夫だよ。
But it'll be okay.
僕も　君と一緒に考えるから。
I'll help you think of a solution!
君の大切な友達のために→
Let me help you come up with a way to help your friends too, okay?
どうすればいいか
僕にも　考えさせておくれよ。
ウーゴくんも　モルさんもいる。
みんなで考えれば→
We have Ugo and Morg on our side too.
If we all work together, I'm sure we can find a better answer!
きっと　今より
いい答えが見つかるはずさ。
アラジン…。
Aladdin...
Okay, Alibaba?
ねっ　アリババくん。
ああ。
Yeah.
うわっ！
（２人）あっ！
♪♪～
Yo! Sorry for the wait.
（カシム）よう。　待たせたな。
へっ。　助けに来たぜ　相棒。
We've come to rescue you, partner.
Kassim!
カシム！
（カシム）あっ？　お前ら　ゆうべの。
I remember you two from last night...
Get 'em! They're all just a bunch of rich pansies!
（団員）
襲え　襲え～！　どうせ　金持ちだ！
I don't know why we're here. Just capture 'em all!
目標の特徴は　分からねぇ！
どんどん　ひっ捕まえろ。
No one told me we were going to attack this hotel!
ホテルを襲うなんて
聞いてねぇぞ！
バカ野郎。　やらなきゃ
こっちが　やられちまうんだよ。
Fool. If we don't get them, they'll get us.
やられる？
情報が入ったんだ。
Get us?
We got some new intel.
このホテルにいるんだよ　あの男→
Sinbad is here
in this hotel!
シンドバッドが。
（ザイナブ）やっちまいな！
Get him!
ガン　ガン　ガン！
（一同）あっ！
（ジャーファル）シン！
（シンドバッド）任せろ！
Sin!
Leave it to me!
ガキン！
（ハッサン）うっ！
You attacked this place knowing who I am and that I was going to be here.
俺が　誰か分かったうえで
仕掛けてきたようだな。
Of course, o' great Sinbad!
（ハッサン）もちろんだ
シンドバッドさんよぉ。
へっ！
なっ！
Oh goodness, you are so helpless!
（ジャーファル）
ああ～　もう！　この役立たず！
うるせぇ！
（ハッサン）ふん！
Shut up!
ドゴッ！
（ハッサン）うっ！　うぅ…→
What was that move?
へっ…　なんだ？　今の…。
ぐはっ！
（ザイナブ）ハッサン！
Hassan!
（ハッサン）ごほっ！　ぐはっ…。
You made me waste my magoi.
余計な魔力を　使わせやがって。
I'll explain later. Let's go!
話は　あとだ。　急げ！
待ってくれ！　俺は…。
Wait! I-
危ねぇ！
バキッ！
Watch out!
（カシム）こっちだ！
This way!
（２人）はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
What are you going to do, Alibaba?
どうするのです!?　アリババさん！
They're still a group of thieves.
彼らは　所詮　盗賊なんですよ。
（カシム）黙れ　化け物女。
また　やられてぇのか？
Shut up, you monster.
Want to get beaten again?
ドーン！
（団員たち）おおっ!?　うわ～！
（カシム）ひるむな。　かかれ！
（団員たち）おお～！
Stand strong!
Get 'em!
Yeah!
マスルール。
（マスルール）了解。→
Masrur.
Yessir.
んん～…。
♪♪～
（団員たち）うわ～！
すごい…。
Wow...
（シンドバッド）
やり過ぎだぞ　マスルール。
You went a little overboard, Masrur.
（カシム）な…　なんだ？　お前たちは！
Who are you guys?
What do you mean? Did you come here looking for me?
（シンドバッド）
何って　俺を捜しに来たんだろ？
I see. So you're Sinbad!
そうか…　お前が！　ふん！
（シンドバッド）うっ…。　なんだ？　これは。
What's this stuff?
（カシム）
動けば動くほど　締め上げるぞ。→
The more you struggle, the tighter it'll bind you!
Hear that? No one move!
いいか！　誰も動くんじゃねぇ！
助けないと。
I should save him.
（ジャーファル）無用です。
No need.
♪♪～
（カシム）バカな！
（ジャーファル）七海の覇王の名は→
No way!
His title as High King of the Seven Seas isn't just for show.
だてじゃありません。
（シンドバッド）この程度の　魔法道具は→
Such a weak magical item won't affect me.
俺には　効かないよ。
Damn you!
くっそ～～!!→
うっ！
カシム！
Kassim!
Now, once I capture you, my work here'll be done.
（シンドバッド）
さて　あとは　君を捕まえれば→
俺の仕事は　終わりだ。→
Right, Miracle Man Alibaba?
なっ　怪傑アリババ君。
くっ！
（シンドバッド）大将同士
決着を　つけようじゃないか。→
Let's settle this as leaders. What do you say?
Feel free to use your weapon, Dungeon Capturer.
なんなら　出せばいい。
攻略者なんだろう？
≪マジかよ…　シンドバッド？≫
No way, he's Sinbad?
The legendary Dungeon Capturer?
≪伝説の迷宮攻略者じゃねぇか≫
≪アラジン
どうして動かないの？≫
Why isn't Aladdin doing anything?
Alibaba's in danger!
≪アリババさんが　危ないのに≫
（カシム）アリババ　逃げろ！→
Run for it, Alibaba!
Men! Make sure our leader makes it out alive!
野郎ども
俺たちの頭領を　逃がすんだ！
（シンドバッド）
なるほど　それも　一つの手だ。→
I see. You have that option as well.
The Fog Troupe is doomed for anyway,
どうせ　霧の団は終わりだし→
and you're different from the likes of them.
考えてみれば　君は
こいつらとは違う人間だものな。→
If you want to run, run.
逃げたければ　逃げるがいい。
あっ。
They're all people from the slums.
（シンドバッド）
彼らは　スラム街の人間だ。→
だが　君は違う。→
But you're not.
いくら
そのふりをしようとしても→
Even if you pretend to be one of them,
you can't escape the fact that you're a prince.
君は　所詮　王子様だ。
黙れ!!
Shut up!
知ったふうな口　利くんじゃねぇ！
Don't talk like you know me!
俺と　こいつらに
何一つ　違いなんてねぇ。
I'm no different from them!
They're all my brothers and sisters!
みんな　俺の大切な兄弟たちだよ！
それを…→
Don't you make fun of the bonds we share!
その絆を　バカにすんじゃねぇ～!!
Spirit of propriety and discipline,
礼節と厳格の精霊よ→
I command thee and thine.
汝と　汝の眷属に命ず。
With my magoi as your source,
我が魔力を糧として→
Use your great power to bring my will to life!
我が意志に　大いなる力を与えよ。
Come forth, Amon!
出でよ　アモン！
I'll beat him! I don't care if he's Sinbad!
≪やってやる…
相手が　シンドバッドだろうと！≫
≪霧の団は　終わらせねぇ≫
As long as I still have power,
I won't let the Fog Troupe end like this!
この力があるかぎり！
So this is the fire djinn, Amon.
≪これが　アモン…　炎のジンか≫
♪♪～
≪バルバッド流王宮剣術≫
He fights using Balbadd's royal sword style.
♪♪～
He's not too bad at combining his moves with Amon's flames either.
≪炎とのコンビネーションも
悪くない≫
ぐっ！
ガキン！
♪♪～
≪ほ…　炎が…≫
T-The flames!
ドゴッ！
ぐわっ！
アリババ～!!
（団員たち）おっ…。
Alibaba!
You don't seem to understand how to use a djinn.
君は　ジンの使い方を
まるで分かっていない。
悪ぃ…　カシム。
I'm sorry, Kassim...
俺…　ごほっ　ごほっ…。
I...
Dammit!
ちくしょ～～!!
Why did you have to show up here?
なんで
あんたなんかが出てくんだよ!?
シンドリアは　関係ねぇだろ。
This has nothing to do with Sindria!
あんたが来なきゃ
俺たちは　負けなしだったのに！
If it weren't for you, we'd still be undefeated!
（シンドバッド）それは
内通者から　情報をもらって→
If you didn't have someone on the inside leaking
information to you, you wouldn't be able to do anything!
うまいこと
やっていただけだろうが。
己の無力さも分からない愚か者が。
Know your place, you foolish weakling!
お前は　勝てないケンカに
周りを巻き込み→
You've involved all those around you in a fight you can't win.
You're just leading them to their doom!
破滅させようとしていただけだ！
くっ…。
捕らえられたら
彼らは　どうなるのですか？
If they're captured, what will happen to them?
It may be harsh, but the fate of a rebel is to die by the noose.
（ジャーファル）厳しいですが
反逆者の末路は　処刑台です。
But if you still desire to fight, even knowing all of that, there is one path left to you.
（シンドバッド）
だが　それでも戦うというなら→
お前らには
もう一つ　道が残されている。
Huh?
ん？
（シンドバッド）欠けているものを→
You must gain what it is you lack.
補うこと。　すなわち→
In other words, you must allow me to join the Fog Troupe!
この俺を
霧の団の仲間にすることだ。
（一同）あっ…。
（ジャーファル）ええっ!?
What?
Sin, you're going to join the Fog Troupe?
（ジャーファル）
シン…　あなたが霧の団に？
（シンドバッド）ああ。
（ジャーファル）それで　戦う？
Yeah.
And fight with them?
（シンドバッド）ああ。
（ジャーファル）バルバッド国と？
Against the government of Balbadd?
（シンドバッド）ああ！
（ジャーファル）あっ…。
Yeah!
That makes no sense.
それは　おかしい。
霧の団は　倒すべき敵です。
You're supposed to defeat the Fog Troupe.
Did you agree with Ahbmad to do so in order to reopen trade?
貿易再開のため　アブマド王と
約束したではありませんか。
But I want to support the Fog Troupe.
だが　俺は
霧の団に　味方したくなったのだ。
あんた
言ってること　変わってますよ！
That's not what you said earlier!
自分で考えて決めたとか→
Didn't you say that's your story and you're
sticking to it? What happened to your resolve?
かっこいいこと
言ってたじゃないですか！
はぁ…。　ジャーファル君→
Oh Jafar...
お前は　なんて冷酷な男なんだ！
（ジャーファル）えっ…　ええ～っ!?
How can you be so coldhearted?
What?!
You heard too, didn't you?
（シンドバッド）お前も知ったろう？
この国の惨状を。
About the terrible things happening in this country!
（ジャーファル）ええ。
（シンドバッド）それでも　なお→
Yes...
Yet in spite of all of that, your heart does not move?
お前の心は
動かなかったというのか!?
そりゃ…　確かに→
Uh, well, I mean, I do think terrible things are happening...
ひどいとは思いましたが…。
（シンドバッド）だろう!?
Exactly!
≪なんで　私が悪者に…≫
Why am I the bad guy here?
That's why I decided that I'd rather
だから　俺は思ったのだ
あのバカ王よりも→
lend my strength to these people desperately fighting for the slums,
スラムのために　必死で戦う
こいつらの力になりたいと。
than to that stupid king.
俺は　霧の団と共に戦うぞ。
I will fight with the Fog Troupe!
What is this guy saying?
≪この人　一体…≫
Mister Sinbad's an interesting guy, isn't he?
変わった人だね
シンドバッドおじさんって。
I can see how he became so famous!
とっても
有名人になっちゃうのは→
僕　分かるよ。
そうですか？
Can you?
So do you think you could let me join, Alibaba?
というわけで
入団を　認めてくれるかな？
アリババ君。
悪いけど→
Sorry, but I've seen too much to fall for something like that.
それを信じるほど
俺は　もう　甘くねぇつもりなんだ。
If I said I just wanted to help the people of
this country, you still wouldn't believe me?
（シンドバッド）
ただ　この国の民を助けたいだけ→
と言っても　信じられないか？→
Well...
そうだな…
ほかにも　理由があるとすれば→
I do have another reason.
I want to stop the abnormalities that are happening around the world.
それは
世界の異変を　止めるためだ。
Have you not noticed them?
君たちは　感じないか？
In recent years, wars have been
happening with much greater frequency,
近年　戦争が頻発し
貧困や差別は　拡大し→
and poverty and discrimination have become worse than ever.
The world is becoming covered in chaos.
世界が　混乱に　満ち満ちていると。
♪♪～
Kou
As the King of Sindria, I am very concerned about the current situation of things.
（シンドバッド）俺は　シンドリア王として
この状況を　憂えている。→
だから　世界異変の一つである
このバルバッドの内乱を→
I want to resolve the internal strife in Balbadd because it is one of these abnormalities.
解決したいと思っている。
How is that reason?
それで　どうだろうか？
What does he want me to say to that?
≪どうって…。
何なんだ？　この人は≫
≪いきなり　世界とか…≫
He suddenly brings up the entire world...
Don't let him fool you!
（カシム）
だまされんな！　国王のくせに→
What would a king want to do with us!
何が　俺たちの仲間だ！→
Those up there like him would love it if little,
dirty, peasant folk like us all starved to death!
てめぇら上の人間は
俺たちみてぇな　汚ぇ下の人間が→
飢えて死のうが
いいと思ってんだろ！
自分たちが
ぜいたくに暮らすためならよぉ。
As long as he could continue living his own comfy, cushy life!
違うか？　ええっ!?
シンドバッドさんよぉ！→
Am I wrong, o' great Sinbad?
あっ！　あぁ…。
Shut up.
黙れ。
♪♪～
A petty thief like you knows nothing of the scars Sin bears,
シンが　どれほどの傷を負い→
自分を犠牲にして生きてきたか→
the sacrifices Sin's made...
知りもしない野盗ごときが。
うっ！
やめろ　ジャーファル。
あっ。
Jafar, stop.
（ジャーファル）すみません。
（シンドバッド）ああ。
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
分かった。　もう　やめてくれ。
I get it. Stop.
So you'll let me join? Thanks.
（シンドバッド）じゃあ　仲間に
してくれるんだな？　ありがとう。
ああ…。
くっ！
Mister Jafar is a little scary.
ジャーファルおにいさんは
ちょっと怖い人だったんだね。
（マスルール）まあ…　時々。
Only sometimes.
（シンドバッド）
では　早速だが　アリババ君→
Well, let's get straight to business.
Alibaba, I want you to come with me to the royal palace.
君には　俺と
バルバッド王宮に行ってもらう。
You said that once you earned the support of the people,
（シンドバッド）
君は　民衆の支持を得たら→
身分を明かし　アブマドと
話をつけるつもりなのだろう？→
you would reveal your identity and talk with Ahbmad, right?
Now's the perfect time for that.
それが　今だということだよ。→
霧の団の頭領として
すでに　民衆の支持は得ているし→
As the leader of the Fog Troupe, you've
already gained the support of the people,
and I will support your claim as a prince of Balbadd.
王子としての身分は
俺が保証しよう。
俺は
先王とは　古い知り合いでね。→
I'm an old friend of the late king.
うん…
君は　先王に　よく似ているよ。→
And I can see his resemblance in you.
You are, without a doubt, a prince of Balbadd.
紛れもなく　バルバッド王子だ。→
And as a prince, you carry a heavy responsibility, don't you?
だから　君には
重い責任があるんじゃないのか？
カシム君もいいね？
話し合いが　まとまれば→
You agree with this, don't you Kassim?
If the negotiations go well, we'll be able to
protect the lives of those living in the slums.
スラムの人々の生活は
保障される。→
それが　君たちの
望んでいたことなのだろう？
That's your goal, isn't it?
（カシム）好きにしろよ。
Whatever.
Kassim...
カシム…。
行っておいでよ　アリババくん。
You should go, Alibaba.
You're a hero. I know that for a fact.
君は勇気ある人じゃないか。
僕は知ってる。
ん？　「告げる。→
"Notice"?
国を憂いし者は　本日正午→
"Attention all those who are discontented."
"Gather today at noon at the royal palace."
王宮に集まられたし」。
"Today, with all of you as my witnesses,
I will gain an audience with King Ahbmad,
「皆の前で
我は　アブマド王に謁見し→
この国の行く末について→
and discuss the future of this country until a satisfactory answer can be reached."
存分に　話し合う所存なり」。
これは　期待していいのか？
Can we expect anything from something like this?
「霧の団頭領　怪傑アリババこと→
Signed "Leader of the Fog Troupe, Miracle Man
Alibaba and Third Prince of Balbadd, Alibaba Saluja."
バルバッド国
第三王子アリババ・サルージャ」。
怪傑アリババが王子！
Miracle Man Alibaba's a prince?
こいつは　すごいぞ。
行こうぜ。
That really is a miracle!
Let's go!
ああ！
王宮へ。
Yeah!
To the palace!
♪♪～
こんなに集まるなんて。
I can't believe there are this many people...
Their numbers are the proof of the
despair felt at the reign of the current king,
（シンドバッド）
人々が　いかに　君に期待し→
今の国王に
絶望しているかの証しだ。
and the hope they have in you.
Let their voices be your strength.
彼らの声を　自分の力にしたまえ。
はい。
All right.
So you're the one who caused this fuss, Sinbad?
（アブマド）この騒ぎを仕掛けたのは
おじさんでしね？
俺は　内政干渉はしない主義だ。
I don't plan on interfering.
話は　兄弟同士でつけてくれ。
Please settle this between yourselves, brothers Saluja.
（アブマド）もう　さんざん　ちょっかい
出していて　何言ってるでし！
How can you say that with a straight face!
How much meddling have you done already?
♪♪～
アブマド兄さん。
ふん…。
Brother Ahbmad.
（サブマド）
は…　話を聞いてやろうよ　兄さん。
You should hear him out, Ahbmad.
アリババは
ちゃんと話せるヤツだから。
Alibaba's a sensible guy. I'm sure he has his reasons.
僕は　知ってるから。
ん？
兄さん　知ってると思うけど→
Trust me.
宝物庫の件は　俺のせいだ。
Brother, I'm sure you're already aware,
父上が亡くなったのも
俺が原因も同然だ。
but the incident with the royal treasury was my fault.
あのとき　俺は
消せない罪を犯したと思っている。
As such, I also bear the blame for father's death.
でも　なぜ
霧の団が　宝物庫を襲ったのか→
I know that I committed an unforgivable crime.
今　みんなが
王宮に押し寄せているのか…。
But I want you to think about why the Fog
Troupe attacked the royal treasury that day,
and why the people are all gathering at the royal palace today!
考えてくれ！　あんたの国民は今→
Your citizens are suffering!
死ぬほど苦しんでるんだ！
Brother Ahbmad, I ask you as the King of this country.
アブマド兄さん
国王としての　あんたに頼む。
国民の生活を　これからは
全力で守ると約束してくれ！
Please promise me you'll do everything in
your power to protect the lives of its people!
If you do, I promise to disband the Fog Troupe!
そうすれば
俺は　霧の団を解散する。
言いたいことは　それだけか？
カツン
Is that all you wanted to say?
あっ　待てよ！　約束は…。
Wait! Is it a promise?!
（アブマド）無礼ぞ。
はっ。
Insolence.
（アブマド）下賤の輩が
許しなく　正統なる王の前で→
You brat of common birth, do not dare to
speak without permission in front of the king.
口を開くな。
あぁ…。
I am the 23rd King of Balbadd, Ahbmad Saluja.
余は　第２３代バルバッド国王→
アブマド・サルージャであるぞ。→
I have never considered you, something we picked up from the slums, as my brother.
スラムの拾い子を
弟などと思うたことはない。→
そちの首
シンドリア王の加護なくば→
Do not forget.
If it were not for the protection of the King of Sindria, your head would have long be severed from your shoulders.
とうに飛んでいること　忘れるな。
Now leave! I don't feel well.
下がれ！　余は　気分が悪い。
王宮の外に
ウジが　たくさん湧いて…。
There are maggots swarming the palace grounds...
ふざけるな～!!
Screw you!
Someone who speaks of his people like that has no right to be king!
自分の国民を
そんなふうにぬかすお前に→
王の資格なんてない!!
Oh my.
≫（銀行屋）おや～？
これは　なんの騒ぎですかな？
What's all the commotion?
Oh, you've returned, Banker.
おお～　戻ったのか　銀行屋。
♪♪～
アリババくん　大丈夫かな？
I wonder if Alibaba's okay in there.
こんなに　国民の人々に
支持されているんですから→
With the support of all these people, I'm sure he's fine.
きっと　大丈夫です。
そうだね。
Yeah, you're right.
What's with this swarm of people?
（ジュダル）なんだよ？　この人だかり。
♪♪～
≪なんだろう？　今　一瞬だけ→
What was that?
It was only for a split second, but
that man appeared to be a black sun.
あの人が
黒い太陽に見えた気がした≫
♪♪～
nozoite miyou
Take a look
yubi bouenkyou
through your finger telescope.
me ni mieru sekai ha subete kako no monogatari sa
The world you see before your eyes is a story already told.
♪♪～
kagayaku mirai wo miushinau na yo
Don't lose sight of the bright future ahead.
♪♪～
kimi ni ha motto ippai yume to kibou ga arun da
You're destined to realize great hopes and dreams.
bootto shitetara minogashichau zo
But if you blink for too long, they'll leave you behind.
♪♪～
dekinai riyuu sagasu yori
Instead of searching for an excuse,
yatte mireba ii
why not just give it a try?
♪♪～
nozoite miyou
Take a look
yubi bouenkyou
through your finger telescope.
yubi to yubi wo marume ryoume ni ate
Make circles with your fingers and put them around your eyes.
imeeji shite sagashiteru mono
Picture your hopes and dreams!
♪♪～
atama no naka no adobenchaaa
Picture your personal adventure story!
doko he mukau?
Where are you headed?
yubi bouenkyou
What can you see
♪♪～
yubi no sono sukima ni nani ga mieru?
in the space between your fingers?
tooi you demo hontou ha chikai
It might seem far, but it's really not.
yogen no you na takaramono
It's a promise as valuable as any treasure!
Play with me more, little Magi!
I feel it clearly. I must stop this man no matter what.
Next time: His Name is Judal.
10th Night
His Name is Judal
Aw man, another weird guy takes the stage!
（ジュダル）
もっと　俺と遊べよ　チビのマギ！
はっきりと分かる。　僕は
この人を　止めなくてはならない。
なんか　また　濃いヤツ　きた～！
今朝、山梨県内の中央自動車道上
り線の
笹子トンネルで天井が崩れ落ち
少なくとも車３台が下敷きになっ
た。
このうちワゴン車から、これまで
に３人の遺体が確認されたほか